Welcome to this next very important section.
And it's a section on functions, functions and libraries and everything associated with them.
Now what is a function.
Well, quite simply it's a reusable block of code.
You know, like things we're in the new age where things need to be reusable.
We don't want to throw things away and have wastage, etc. so it's great when you can take one item
and use it over and over and over again, especially when it comes to things like straws.
We're in this area.
We've got to end the plastic straws.
So rather have a straw that is made out of a glass or bamboo or something else that you can reuse.
That's the error.
And it's the exact same thing when it comes to coding.
Now you haven't realised it, but you've been using functions already.
There are lots of inbuilt functions that Python has like print.
Print is a function.
Now actually what's happening is it's a little block of code that is telling Python what to do, but
you don't have to understand all the intricacies of how it worked and how it makes something display
on the screen.
All you had to do was tell it what you wanted to print, so you would pass a value to print, and it
would then print on the screen.
But now you can create user defined functions.
So not all functions have to be those that are created by the system itself.
You can make your own functions.
Why would you want to do that?
Well the reason you would like to do that is because once you've made it once, you can use it over
and over and over again.
It's like getting rid of those plastic straws.
It is a very useful thing to do.
So we want to show you how you can create functions, how you use functions, because they allow you
to build code in a modular fashion.
It's like having the bricks, the building blocks that you can just cobble together and start to produce
your code.
So in this section we're going to look at functions and how they are so powerful and very important
when it comes to coding in Python.